<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>feats</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Xenirath/XENBuilder/main/XENBuilder/feats.xml" />
		</update>
  	</info>
	<element name="Shadowy Boi" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_SHADOWY_BOI">
		<description>
			<p>You are a being made of shadows. You gain the following benefits while in dim light or darkness:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
				<li>You can use a bonus action to channel and teleport up to 90ft to another dim or dark place that you can see.</li>
				<li>While channeling, you are defenseless, triggering attacks of opportunity from nearby enemies. Attacks of opportunity don't cancel the teleportation.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use a bonus action to channel and teleport up to 90ft to another dim or dark place that you can see.
			While channeling, you are defenseless, triggering attacks of opportunity from nearby enemies. Attacks of opportunity don't cancel the teleportation.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed:misc" value="10" />
			<stat name="innate speed:climb:misc" value="10" requirements="[innate speed:climb:1]" />
			<stat name="innate speed:fly:misc" value="10" requirements="[innate speed:fly:1]" />
			<stat name="innate speed:swim:misc" value="10" requirements="[innate speed:swim:1]" />
			<stat name="innate speed:burrow:misc" value="10" requirements="[innate speed:burrow:1]" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Anti-Component Caster" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_ANTI_COMPONENT_CASTER_VARIANT">
		<supports/>
		<prerequisite> The ability to cast at least one spell.</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: The ability to cast at least one spell.</i></p>
			<p>Your knowledge of spells allows you to cast spells without specific components, granting you the following benefits:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>-You can cast spells without material components if there are no components that are consumed by a spell.</li>
			<li>-You can cast spells without verbal components.</li>
			<li>-You can cast spells without somatic components.</li>
			<li>You may forgo 2 of these 3 features for the alternative benefit of:</li>
			<li>-Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
		</ul>        
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Anti-Component_Caster,_Variant_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description> You get to choose either 3 benefits, or 1 and an ASI.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Anti-Component Caster, Variant" supports="Anti-Component Caster, Variant" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Full Benefits" type="Feat Feature" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_ANTI_COMPONENT_CASTER_VARIANT_FULL">
		<supports>Anti-Component Caster, Variant</supports>
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p> In this case, you get all 3 benefits from the Anti-Component Caster, Variant feat.(no verbal, somatic or non-consumed components needed)</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> No verbal, somatic, or non-consumed material components needed in your spellcasting. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Single Benefit and ASI" type="Feat Feature" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_ANTI_COMPONENT_CASTER_VARIANT_ASI">
		<supports>Anti-Component Caster, Variant</supports>
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>In this case, you get one benefit of your choosing, and a +1 to either Intelligence, Wisdom or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> ASI and one of the benefits from the feat (either verbal, somatic or component ignored while spellcasting).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Anti-Component Caster, Variant" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cantrip Collector" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_CANTRIP_COLLECTOR">
		<supports />
			<prerequisite>Ability to cast at least 1 spell.</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: Ability to cast at least 1 spell.</i></p>
			<p>Your time in the presence of wizards has allowed you to learn the following four cantrips: Mage Hand, Mending, Message and Prestidigitation. These spells do not count against your number of spells known.</p>    
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Cantrip_Collector_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain the Mage Hand, Mending, Message and Prestidigitation cantrips.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
		</rules>
  	</element>
 	<element name="Determinator" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_DETERMINATOR">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>Wisdom 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
		<description>
	 		<p><i>Prerequisites: Wisdom 13 or higher</i></p>
			<p>With the power of sheer determination and willpower, you cling onto your life even in the brink of death. You gain the following benefits:</p>
	 	<ul>
			<li>You have advantage on death saving throws.</li>
			<li>When you take a damage that reduces your hit point to 0, if you are not killed outright from the damage, you drop to 1 hit point instead. Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest to use it again.</li>
  		</ul>        
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Determinator_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description> You get advantage on death saving throws, and once per long rest can drop to 1hp instead of 0 if not killed outright.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Full Counter" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_FULL_COUNTER">
		<supports />
			<prerequisite>Dexterity 13 or higher.</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[dex:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Reflect attacks aimed at you back at your enemy, but with double the power.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When selecting this feat, pick either magical or physical attacks. Upon being hit by either a magical or melee attack, you can use your reaction to reflect double the damage onto the attacker. You regain the use of this ability after a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Full_Counter_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can return either a magical or physical attack, at double the power, back at your enemy once per long rest. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Interposing Reaction" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_INTERPOSING_REACTION">
		<supports />
			<prerequisite>Constitution 13 or higher, Dexterity 13 or higher.</prerequisite>
			<requirements>([con:13],[dex:13])</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: Constitution 13 or higher, Dexterity 13 or higher.</i></p>
			<p>You have gained the reaction time to save your friends from danger, no matter what happens to you:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>You increase your Constitution by 1 point, to a maximum of 20.</li>
			<li>When you see an ally within your range of movement being attacked, you can choose to take their place for the blow, knocking the ally prone in a square adjacent to you and free of harm. This attack hits you no matter your AC, and you take damage as if it had. This includes spell attacks, melee attacks, and ranged attacks.</li>
		</ul>        
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Interposing_Reaction_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can choose to take an ally's place when you see them get hit by a spell, melee or range attack. You knock your ally prone into a safe place, and take the whole blow, no matter your AC, it hits.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lustful Caress" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_LUSTFUL_CARESS">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>Tiefling, Charisma 16 or higher.</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_RACE_TIEFLING, [cha:16]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: Tiefling, Charisma 16 or higher.</i></p>
			<p>After sensing your fiendish lineage pulse with dark power years ago, you've been training in the magic of lust. By touching someone with a tiny bit of your saliva, sweat or cum, you can use an action to attempt to seduce them, increasing their libido and deeply charming them for a duration of your concentration (max 1 hour). </p>
			<ul>
				<li>The creature must have an intelligence of 5 or more, and must make a wisdom saving throw against your spell DC (8 + prof + cha mod). </li>
				<li>If the creature saves, the creature becomes immune to this charm for the next 24 hours. </li>
				<li>If the creature fails, they become charmed and are deeply seduced for an hour; if the target receives damage directed from someone outside the party and allies, the target gets to save again.</li> 
				<li>Also, if the caster does something bad or trully harmful to them (safe BDSM doesn't count), or the caster loses concentration or becomes unconscious, then the spell instantly ends.</li>
				<li>The caster can end the spell as a bonus action. Only one creature can be affected by the charm at a time, and if the spell is cast or affects another creature, the first creature will stop being affected.</li>
				<li>When the spell ends, the affected creature realizes magic was used on them, but if treated well during the spell, they might not be hostile or even angry about it.</li>
			</ul>
	  		<p>While concentrating on the spell, the effect on a creature can be reinforced without ending it. To do so, you must reapply the saliva and use another use of this feature, and the target must make a wisdom saving throw with disadvantage against your spell dc. If they fail, the charm's time (an hour) is reset. If they succeed, the spell ends, wasting that use. You can use this feature an amount of times equal to your CHAmod per short or long rest.</p>    
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl"> </set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description> You gain the ability to deeply seduce a creature. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Magic Initiate, Variant" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>At least 8 levels in a single spellcasting class.</prerequisite>
		<requirements>([type:spell],[level:8])</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: Ability to cast at least 1 spell and play at least 1 instrument</i></p>
			<p>Choose a spellcasting class: bard, cleric, druid, sorcerer, warlock, wizard</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You learn two cantrips of your choice from that class spell list and may add the appropriate spellcasting ability modifier to the damage of these two cantrips.</li>
				<li>In addition, you learn the spell Find Familiar and, using this feat, can cast it at its lowest level to call a Pseudodragon. Once you cast it in this way, you must finish a long rest before you can cast it in this way again.</li>
				<li>Your spellcasting ability for these spells depends on the class you chose: Charisma for bard, sorcerer, or warlock; Wisdom for cleric or druid; or Intelligence for wizard.</li>
			</ul>        
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Magic_Initiate,_Variant_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn two cantrips from a spellcasting class of your choosing, may add the respective modifiers to their damage, and can cast Find Familiar once per long rest using this feat to call a Pseudodragon.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat Feature" name="Magic Initiate, Variant" supports="Magic Initiate, Variant" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bard" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_BARD">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the bard's spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Charisma.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate)" supports="0,Bard" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cleric" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_CLERIC">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the cleric's spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is wisdom.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Wisdom.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate)" supports="0,Cleric" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Druid" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_DRUID">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is wisdom.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Wisdom.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate)" supports="0,Druid" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sorcerer" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_SORCERER">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the sorcerer's spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Charisma.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate)" supports="0,Sorcerer" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Warlock" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_WARLOCK">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the warlock's spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Charisma.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate)" supports="0,Warlock" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wizard" type="Feat Feature" source="Player's Handbook" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_MAGIC_INITIATE_VARIANT_WIZARD">
		<supports>Magic Initiate, Variant</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard's spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your spellcasting ability for these spells is intelligence.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spellcasting ability: Intelligence.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Magic Initiate, Variant)" supports="0,Wizard" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Silent Performance" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_SILENT_PERFORMANCE">
		<supports />
			<prerequisite>Ability to cast at least 1 spell and play at least 1 instrument</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisites: Ability to cast at least 1 spell and play at least 1 instrument</i></p>
			<p>As a magical caster and performer you've spent several hours practicing your craft to be as unique and useful as possible. This allows you to gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Wisdom or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency in Performance. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li>When casting a spell with a verbal component you may make a Performance check against viewers' passive (Perception). If you are successful they are unaware of a spell being cast and believe it is just a performance. If you succeed by 5 or more you can choose to have the performance be silent.</li>
			</ul>        
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Silent_Performance_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain proficiency or expertise in Performance, can perform, replacing the verbal component of a spell, and can make it silent for other creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Silent Performance" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERFORMANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Snap Shooter" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_SNAP_SHOOTER">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>Dexterity or Strength of 13 or higher.</prerequisite>
		<requirements>([str:13]|[dex:13])</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>While wielding a ranged weapon with which you are proficient, you threaten squares within 5 feet of you. You can make attacks of opportunity with that ranged weapon. You do not provoke attacks of opportunity when making a ranged attack as an attack of opportunity. Additionally, the area of space you threaten with opportunity attacks increases with your ability score as follows:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>13 - You threaten an area of 5 ft.</li>
				<li>15 - You threaten an area of 10 ft.</li>
				<li>17 or higher - You threaten an area of 15 ft.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Snap_Shooter_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your AoO reactions can be ranged, and you threaten an area that increases with your Dexterity or Strenght score.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Thrifty Caster" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_THRIFTY_CASTER">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>Ability to cast at least 1 spell.</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[type:spell]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your knowledge of spells allows you to cast spells without materials, granting you the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You can cast spells without material components if the combined cost of the materials is less than 250 gp.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Thrifty_Caster_(5e_Feat)</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>Ignore material components if the combined cost is less than 250gp.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Thrifty Caster" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Trained Blindsight" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_TRAINED_BLINDSIGHT">
		<supports />
		<prerequisite>Being completely blind and having trained your other senses for years.</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p>After being born blind or losing you sight as a child or many years ago, you tried to better your other senses to superhuman levels. Or maybe you have something special that allows you to detect without sight, such as a bats echolocation. You can change how the blindsight exactly works with your DM, depending on what you want it to be.</p>
			<p>When you choose this feat, you gain the following traits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You lose all normal / natural sight, and you gain <b>Blindsight</b> with a radius of 30ft. You cannot see anything past this radius unless you use special or magical means to do so, but can hear or smell like normal.</li>
				<li>You automatically fail all checks that rely  <b>entirely</b> on sight, and have disadvantage on any checks that rely <b>mostly</b> on sight.</li>
				<li>You have <b>disadvantage</b> on any saving throw against <b>sudden</b> loud sounds or powerful smells, such as the sound created by the Thunderwave spell.</li>
				<li>You are <b>immune</b> to conditions or effects that require sight, such the blind condition, gaze effects, invisibility or darkness of any kind. You are also <b>vulnerable</b> to Thunder damage.</li>
				<li>You have <b>advantage</b> on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell, hearing or touch.</li>
				<li>Once on your turn, you can use a <b>bonus action</b> to try to focus your senses. If you succeed, your Blindsight radius <b>increases</b> to 60ft until the start of your following turn. You can do this a number of times equal to Wisdom modifier, and recharges on a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Through training, you gained blindsight.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT"/>	
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Xen's Familiar Buddy" type="Feat" source="Xenirath" id="ID_XENIRATH_FEAT_XENS_FAMILIAR_BUDDY">
		<prerequisite></prerequisite>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your charm or quirkiness has called a curious spirit, which is now bonded to you, granting you the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You learn the Find Familiar spell, which can cast without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can cast it in this way again.</li>
				<li>When choosing your familiar’s form, you can choose any beast or monstrosity up to CR 1/4. </li>
				<li>While you are touching your familiar, you can change its form as an action, without needing to cast the spell.</li>
				<li>While touching your familiar, you can also change it's type, as an action, from another type on the list, without needing to cast the spell. The list of types is also expanded to the following: aberration, celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, undead.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your charm or quirkiness has called a curious spirit, which is now bonded to you. You can cast the Find Familiar spell once per long rest for free, to summon a beast or monstrosity up to CR 1/4. It's form and type can be changed as an action while touching the familiar.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
			<select type="Companion" name="Buddy" supports="Familiar"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
