<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
        <name>spells</name>
		<update version="0.0.6">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Xenirath/XENBuilder/main/XENBuilder/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Magnet Orb" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_MAGNET_ORB">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock, Bard</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">You conjure an orb that pulls foes towards it.</p>
			<p>You create a magical orb of iron at a point of your choice within range. The orb is 3 feet in diameter, and floats 2 feet above the ground. Each creature that starts it's turn within 20 feet of the orb must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be pulled 10 feet towards the orb. Any creature within 20 feet of the orb must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving away from the orb. Any creature that touches the orb must make a Strenght saving throw or take 1d10 lightning damage. Unattended inanimate objects that weigh 5 pounds or less within 20 feet of the orb are also pulled towards it at a rate of 10 feet per round. The caster cannot be affected by the orb's effect.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels. </i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the maximum range that the orb's pulling can reach increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A small nugget of iron</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Rend" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_ARCANE_REND">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor"> You rip the weave from someone to attack another target.</p>
			<p> Make a ranged spell attack against a creature 30 feet from you. That creature, if not willing, must make a wisdom saving throw. If it fails, they take 1d10 force damage, and you must select another creature within 30 feet of the target to also take the same damage. If the creature is willing, both chained creatures instead take 2d10. The first target also loses a spell slot (if it has any) of a level equal to the casting of this spell. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels. </i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet, then another 30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">A drop of goblin blood.</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Blink" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_SHADOW_BLINK">
		<supports>Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">You meld with the shadows around you, which provides you with extra movement.</p>
			<p>You become shrouded in shadow and for the duration after casting this spell you gain the ability to meld with the darkness for the purpose of travelling around an area, unseen. As long as you are standing in an area that is dark or dim lit, you may, on your turn, merge with the darkness, becoming one with it and doubling your movement speed while merged. You can enter and exit any surface including the floor, a wall or the celling as long as it has a shadow large enough for you body. You can emerge from the shadow of any creature considered one size larger than you. The moment you emerge you are considered hidden because you appear as shadow but when you leave the dark area you may be spotted. The shadow you emerge from is tangible to you and you may cling to it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"></set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Xen's Temporal Rush" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_XENS_TEMPORAL_RUSH">
   		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
   		<description>
     			<p>Your body quickens and phases, slightly superimposing itself over the fabric of time itself, and you gain the following effects:</p>
     			<p class="indent"> Your movement speed is doubled.</p>
			<p class="indent"> You get an extra Action on each of your turns.</p>
			<p class="indent"> You have advantage on all of your attacks, and everyone has disadvantage on all </p>
			<p class="indent"> attacks targeting you.</p>
			<p> When this spell ends, your body suffers the consequences of the acceleration, as the fabric of time violently latches onto it again:</p>
     			<p class="indent"> You gain one level of Exhaustion, and you are Paralyzed until the end of your next </p>
			<p class="indent"> turn, as your body's mass gets accustomed to the natural flow of time. </p>
			<p class="indent"> Additionally, make a Constitution saving throw (DC 20). On a failure, you take 4d8 </p>
			<p class="indent"> force damage.</p>
  	 	</description>
  		<setters>
    			<set name="keywords"></set>
   			<set name="level">5</set>
    			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
    			<set name="time">1 action</set>
    			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
    			<set name="range">self</set>
    			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
   			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
   			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
   			<set name="materialComponent">Two hands of a clock, a minute hand and an hour hand, one made of mithril and one of adamantine, tied together with string.</set>
   			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
   			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
  		</setters>
 	</element>  
	<element name="Xen's Transmogrification" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_XENS_TRANSMOGRIFICATION">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor"> Even knowing how flawed they all are, you still want to play god.</p>
			<p> To do this, you encase a humanoid in clay, and start conducting a rigorous, one-hour-long ritual that manipulates (or makes) the flesh and function of the target's body into that of another humanoid race. They lose their previous racial traits and instetad gain the racial traits of another humanoid race of the target's choice, aside from their languages known (which remain unchanged).</p>
			<p> The age and lifespan of the previous race carries over as well, regardless of the longevity of the new race acquired. Should the target wish to alter their gender along with or instead of their race, they can choose to do so as part of the spell.</p>
			<p> When the ritual is completed, both the caster and the target gain one level of exhaustion. Once a creature's race or gender has been changed via this spell, they cannot be affected by this spell again for 1 year.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">Damp clay equal to the weight of the target and 150 gp worth of crushed gem dust, both of which the spell consumes.</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blessed Blade" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_BLESSED_BLADE">
		<supports>Cleric, Druid, Ranger, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell’s range, otherwise the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the weapon attack’s normal effects, and you can channel divine magic into the target. Choose necrotic or radiant damage. The attack deals an additional damage of the chosen type equal to your spellcasting modifier on a hit, plus an additional effect based on the type of damage. If necrotic, the next time target takes damage within the next minute, they take an additional 1d8 necrotic damage, and the effect ends. If radiant, you can choose and additional creature within 15ft of the target, and divine light splashes towards them, dealing 1d8 radiant damage to them.</p>
			<p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases when you reach certain levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an additional 1d8 necrotic or radiant damage to the target on a hit, and the damage dealt by the effects increases to 2d8. Both damage rolls increase by one die at 11th level (2d8 and 3d8) and 17th level (3d8 and 4d8).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (5-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a melee weapon</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Elemental Burst" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BURST">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You hurl a burst of elemental energy at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d4 damage. </p>
			<p>Choose one of the d4s, or roll again (your choice). The number rolled on the die determines the damage type, as shown below.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d4</td><td>Damage Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Thunder</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent">This spell's damage increases by 2d4 when you reach 5th level (4d4), and again at 11th level (6d4) and 17th level (8d4).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Punny Phouk-Act" type="Spell" source="XENBuilder" id="ID_XENBUILDER_SPELL_PUNNY_PHOUK_ACT">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you strike a foe with a melee weapon attack, you can immediately cast Punny Phouk-Act as a bonus action. The joy and magic from the feywild surges from you, granting you armor class 16 + your Dexterity modifer for the spell’s duration. This magical armor has no Strength requirement, doesn’t hinder spellcasting, and doesn’t incur disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the creature you struck was a fey, the armor also grants you advantage on Wisdom saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">feywild magic</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="Blood">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent" addition="you must have just struck a foe with a melee weapon">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"></set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
